My businesses make about $1,500 per
hour, 24 hours a day, 365 days a year,
regardless of what I'm doing. And that
is not an accident. That is because we
have nailed our marketing approach. Our
marketing and sales approach is in line
with the technology trends of today. And
today, in this video, I want to share
with you what is the most important
simple marketing approach that I'm using
across all of my products and services
globally. If we haven't met yet, I'm
Daniel Priestley. For the last 20 years,
I've been building and scaling multiple
startups. I've had seven startups that
have gone zero to a million in their
first 12 months. I've had multiple
businesses go north of 10 million. I've
built companies, sold companies,
>> [music]
>> I've bought companies, I've spun out new
businesses from existing businesses.
I've written seven books on
entrepreneurship. All of that is to say
that I spend a lot of time thinking
about this stuff. The first thing that I
need you to know is how social media has
changed over the last few years, and
it's significant. See, if we go back in
time before 2015, all the attention was
on social media, and the feed that you
would see was chronological.
That meant that if you posted something
regularly, you had more chance of being
seen in the feed. But here's the one big
thing from prior to 2015. 90% of the
people who would see the posts that you
put on social media were your existing
followers that you'd met in the real
world, and you deliberately followed
each other. [music] So, you would follow
someone on social media because you knew
who they were, and then and only then
did you see what they were posting, and
you saw it in a chronological order.
Then, the next era was called
engagement-based sorting.
This was all about seeing things that
people were posting based upon the
engagement. So, once again, you would
have a collection of followers, people
that you had followed or connected with
on social media, but the way that the
algorithm would sort your feed was
through engagement. [music] So, things
that had lots of likes or lots of watch
time or lots of comments would go to the
top, and things that didn't get much
engagement, that would fall down to the
bottom. Once we got into 2020, we
started to see the beginnings of
hyper-targeted sorting and also the
beginnings of AI sorting.
>> [music]
>> Now, what this meant is that on some
platforms like TikTok, rather than
having to have an audience or a group of
followers or subscribers,
the AI algorithm would pump out your
content based on what was trending. And
a big part of this hyper-targeting and a
big part of this AI sorting was all
about trending topics.
What it would do is it would figure out
what each person was interested in as
far as trending topics were concerned,
and it would bring things from all over
the world, and it would try and find the
trending topics that you were going to
be interested in.
>> [music]
>> Now, from 2025 onwards, we are now into
what we call the recommendation engine.
The recommendation engine is a powerful
AI that looks at every single piece of
content, and it matchmakes that piece of
content with the person who should be
seeing it. Someone in Brisbane,
Australia, could make a piece of content
that is absolutely perfect for someone
in Boston, USA, and the recommendation
engine will figure out that that piece
of content from Brisbane needs to be in
front of that person who's in Boston.
This is a magical piece of technology
that will change humanity. The fact that
the AI recommendation engine is
matchmaking people, no matter where they
are on the planet, is wild. And what
this does for your business is equally
incredible. Imagine it like this.
Imagine you had a magical telephone, and
if you pick up that telephone, it will
literally connect you with someone who
wants to buy from you. Wouldn't that be
incredible? How often would you pick up
the phone? You'd probably pick up the
phone non-stop and generate a ton of new
business. Maybe you would even hire
someone whose only job was to pick up
[music] the phone and talk to the people
on the other end of the phone. That's
kind of what the recommendation engine
is doing. It is connecting you with the
person who wants to know what your
business does, and what problem you
solve, and what outcomes you deliver.
It's connecting you with the person
anywhere in the world who's interested
in what you do. I would go so far as to
say the recommendation engine is the
most powerful AI on the planet, and that
large language models are second most
powerful. I know it doesn't feel like
that, because the recommendation engine
is invisible to you
>> [music]
>> and the LLMs are the things that you see
and interact with personally, but the
recommendation engine is directing
traffic, it's directing attention, it's
changing the nature of politics, it's
changing [music] consumer behavior, and
it's doing it all invisibly. Your
business depends upon [clears throat]
you tapping into that recommendation
engine. So, I want to give you a simple
strategy as to how you're going to tap
into the recommendation engine, and I've
been testing this over the last 12
months, and oh my goodness, this has
supercharged marketing. Quick
interruption, if you want to understand
my marketing strategy in detail, come
along to a live environment with other
entrepreneurs. We're going to go through
and I'll talk you through in more detail
about how I do my marketing. I'm running
a live workshop, and we're going to go
through step-by-step my entire strategy.
You'll see behind the curtain, you'll be
able to copy what I'm doing and get the
same results. There'll be a link
somewhere in the description below, and
you'll be able to click the link, book
in, and I'll see you at the live
workshop. Now, let's get back to the
video. So, the strategy is called
short-form, long-form, lead-form.
Short-form content that leads into
long-form content that then directs
people to fill in a form and signal that
they're interested in working [music]
with you. And here's how it's going to
work. Every single day, you're going to
post something that is a short post, and
I'm going to tell you what to post, but
it's going to be a short post every
single day. That short post is then
going to get people to click on a piece
of long-form content, and that long-form
content is going to educate people as to
what to do next, and then that is going
to tell people to click onto a lead
form, where they're going to literally
fill in a form and signal that they want
to do business with you. And all of this
sits on top of the rails of the
recommendation engine. So, it's going to
expand faster than you know what to do
with. So, let's look at short-form
content. There are four things that I
want you to post about when it comes to
short-form content. Short-form content,
I want you to talk about the pain
that your customer would experience if
they don't buy from you.
>> [music]
>> All right? So, this is the pain that
they're currently experiencing, cuz they
don't have your product or service.
Let's say you help people with their
advertising, the pain is that they don't
have enough customers. The pain is that
their revenues are flat. The pain is
that they're talking to the wrong
people. The [music] pain is that they're
sitting around waiting for a referral
that never comes. So, all of that is the
pain point that people might be able
[music] to relate to. The next thing I
want you to talk about is the opposite
of that, which is the prize.
The prize is what would be on the other
side. What would happen [music] if
people did buy from you? What would be
the joyful celebration that they would
have if [music] everything worked
because they bought from you? That's the
prize. What is it that they want to get
to? The third thing is the problem.
And the problem is what has stopped them
in the past from getting the results
that they want. [music] Why is it they
haven't been able to do this? So, let's
say your business does something in the
health and fitness space cuz it's easy
to understand. The pain would be the
pain that you experience by not having
the health or the fitness that you want.
The prize would be what would it feel
like to have the health and fitness, and
the problem is what's stopping you from
getting the health and fitness. The
fourth thing is called news.
Now, the recommendation engine is always
looking for trending news, and anything
you can do to connect [music] what you
do to something that's trending in the
news is going to give you a turbo
charge. So, I want you to think about
pain, prize, problem, and then the news
is going to give you the extra turbo
charge. So, you could talk about pain
that's in the news, prize that's in the
news, problem that's in the news, or
just news stories that relate to what it
is that you do. Now, you need to do
short-form content daily.
And the reason for that is cuz people
see you for the first time when they see
you for the 11th time,
>> [music]
>> which means that if you're posting
anything less than daily, you're not
being seen enough for people to
recognize who you are and what you do.
Remember that people are just scrolling,
scrolling, scrolling. Humans consume 200
billion short-form videos per day. It's
a lot of short-form videos. If they're
scrolling, scrolling, scrolling, it all
turns into noise. They have to be able
to see you 11 times within 90 days in
order to even recognize that you exist.
So, you need to post daily [music] on
this short-form content. This short-form
content is going to invite people to
check out a piece of long-form content.
You might ask people to comment a word
and you will send them the long-form
content, or you might just direct them
to check out a piece of long-form
content [music] that is pinned to the
top of your channel. What are you going
to cover in long-form content? There's
three main [music] things. Number one is
called a proof story.
A proof story is a story that proves you
know what you're talking about. Or it
could be a statistic or a fact or some
research that proves that there is
something worth paying attention to. So,
you might say, I helped someone lose 20
kilos of body fat. Or you might say, I
helped one of my clients go from 2
million to 5 million of revenue in under
2 years. So, a proof story is something
that proves you must know something
worth talking about. Underneath a proof
story
is the success principles.
And the principles are the three to five
things that made [music] that proof
story possible. So, for example, if
you're talking about health and
wellness, you might talk about diet,
exercise, and mindset. So, these [music]
are the big principles that make the
proof story possible.
And the third thing is the process
that you use to engage with your
clients. So, you might say, I do
coaching or I do accountability or I use
software or I do this, that, and the
other. Whatever is the process that you
take people [music] through. So, proof,
principles, process. And all of that
gets covered in a long form piece of
content. Now, in a long form piece of
content, you're explaining to people
that it's possible to get a new result.
I want you to keep in mind, your
customers, they have gaps in their
awareness, they have gaps in their
understanding, and if you can close
those gaps, they're more likely to buy
from you. So, don't assume that they're
mind readers, create long-form explainer
content that explains step-by-step how
something is done. And if people watch
that explainer content, give Give a call
to action to fill in a form. Short form,
long form, lead form. [music] The lead
form is going to contain a special
offer, a product for prospects, or a
promotion. So, a special offer is some
sort of special offer that's currently
running. Maybe it's a discount, maybe
it's a limited-time offer, maybe it's a
new launch campaign. There is a special
offer that people can engage with.
A product for prospects is an easy first
step to working with you. It could be an
introduction workshop, an online
assessment, filling in a wait list,
joining a discussion group, any of those
things are good product for prospects. A
promotion is some sort of thing that's
happening for a limited amount of time
that people can engage with, and it's
going to have an end date.
>> [music]
>> Any offers, product for prospects, or
promotions are great reasons for people
to fill in this lead form. Now, the way
you want to make this super clear for
people is to make sure that the top of
the lead form has a hook that explains
what's going on.
It restates your value proposition, so
people understand if I do this, I will
get this. It states your credibility.
So, it could be customer testimonials,
it could be your qualifications, it
could be research linked to what you do.
And it has a clear call to action
telling people to fill in this form in
order to get started. Now, the lead
form, it's very, very easy for you to do
all of that on ScoreApp. In fact, all of
that thinking is built into the AI tools
on ScoreApp and all the templates on
ScoreApp. So, if you don't currently
have lead forms with your offers and
your promotions and your product for
prospects, just use scoreapp.com to
create all of those lead forms. Now,
once you've got a great lead form and
that lead form converts, you just do
short form every single day, a new piece
of long form every single month, and at
least a new offer every single 90 days.
So, the cadence is short form daily,
long form monthly, new offer every
quarter. Now, the beauty of this is
[music] that embedded in all of the
things that I've asked you to do is all
the information that the AI needs in
order to fuel the recommendation engine
and put that content in front of the
right people. Because when you're
talking about your pain, your prize,
your problem, and the news, it will
figure out who's interested in solving
that problem, who's interested in
getting rid of that pain, who's
interested in getting that prize, and it
will put that short-form content in
front of that person. When they engage
with that content, it'll direct people
over to the long-form content that
educates and entertains them and tells
them and explains to them what it is
they need to do next, and then it
captures the details so that you can
talk to those people. From here, you've
got your sales process. You've often
heard me talk about laps, leads,
appointments, presentations, and sales.
This lead form is the lead that sparks
the sales process. So, there you have
it, a really simple strategy that I'm
using across all of my businesses. Every
single one of my businesses is in
double-digit growth right now because of
short-form, long-form, lead form.
>> [music]
>> We are doing this all the time. You can
check out all the different channels
that I'm involved in. You can look at my
social media. You will see examples of
short-form, long-form, lead form
happening constantly all the time on all
of my social media, and it's working.
Thousands upon thousands of [music]
warm, qualified leads every single month
coming in for all the different
businesses because of this simple
approach: [music] short-form, long-form,
lead form. I want you to implement this
in your business. Okay, if you've
enjoyed this video, come and join me for
the live workshop that I mentioned
earlier, and I'll see you there. Give
this video a like, give the channel a
subscribe, leave a comment, and I'll see
you soon. All the best.